

# Hamza Saeed

**Nationality:** Pakistani (+49) 1778741500 **Date of birth:** 18/08/1998

**Gender:** Male **Email address:** <u>saeedhamza268@gmail.com</u>

in LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/hamza-saeed-47a8b7188

• Address: Kurt-Schumacher Str 32. Apt 325, , 67663 Kaiserslautern (Germany)

#### **ABOUT ME**

Front end developer with one year's experience creating effective websites that give users an immersive and interesting experience. Through my precise and efficient coding, which I was trained about, I have been attempting to fully meet user expectations. I'm determined to enhance my skills, So I can provide best of me.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### Web developer

**Ideatech Software House** [ 01/06/2019 – 31/12/2019 ]

City: Islamabad
Country: Pakistan

- Performed fully dynamic and browser compatible pages with the help of HTML5, CSS3, jQuery and JavaScript.
- Improving user experience and delivering in smoother operations.
- Got experience in building single page application (SPA), flexible web design UI with the help of HTML5 and CSS3.
- Helped Senior developers in order to tackles bugs and produce effective website performance.

#### **Junior Web Developer**

**SOFIT Consultancy (Pvt.) Ltd** [ 01/02/2019 - 31/05/2019 ]

**City:** Rawalpindi **Country:** Pakistan

- Developed frontend of websites using JavaScript and its frameworks like Angular. Js and Ext. Js.
- Produced eye-catching website interfaces by converting UI/UX design frameworks into code with the help of implementing HTML5 and CSS3.
- Also worked with Back End developers, to get an idea about back end developing.

### Internship

National Center of Cyber Security Air University Islamabad [ 25/06/2019 - 05/08/2019 ]

**City:** Islamabad **Country:** Pakistan

- Worked with National Cybercrime and Forensics Lab as Mobile Forensics intern.
- I learned how to work with Linux (installation, commands etc) and how to manage projects on github during the span.

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

### **Bachelors**

Air University [ 01/09/2016 - 25/04/2020 ]

Address: Service Road E-9 / E-8, 44000 Islamabad (Pakistan)

https://www.au.edu.pk/

• I have done Bachelors in Computer Science from Air University Pakistan and I graduated in 2020.

#### **Masters**

Altinbas University [ 01/11/2020 - Current ]

Address: Mahmutbey, Dilmenler Cd. No:26,, 34217 Istanbul (Turkey)

https://international.altinbas.edu.tr/en/

• I have started Masters Degree in Information Technology from Altinbas University Istanbul, Turkey

#### **Masters Thesis Work**

**Technical University of Kaiserslautern** [ 01/04/2022 - Current ]

Address: Erwin-Schrödinger-Straße 52, 67663 Kaiserslautern (Germany)

https://www.uni-kl.de/

### **LANGUAGE SKILLS**

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s): English

# **DIGITAL SKILLS**

# My Digital Skills

CSS3&HTML5 / JavaScript / jQuery / Frontend Frameworks (e.g. Angular) / UI design / Adobe Illustrator / Adobe Photoshop / Adobe Primerpro / Visual Studio

### **HOBBIES AND INTERESTS**

2D Animation, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Aftereffect, Blender, Hiking, Swimming